

ALEJANDRO VALENCIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND FOCUSED)



WWW.VALENCIAHQ.COM



https://www.linkedin.com/in/valenci aalejandro/



HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/VALENCIAHQ/



alejandro.d.valencia@gmail.com



EXPERTIES

- Good practices
- Teamwork
- Research
- Communication
- Adaptable
- Innovative
- Mentoring

HI!

I've been a software engineer for over 10 years, from 2017 I focused my career path mostly on Frontend. I'm a team player but I also know how to be independent. I do like mentoring, ordering, clean code, and research.

I'm interested in web development, front-end architecture, 3D environments, gaming, and frontend trending libraries and frameworks.

I do know that very cool things happen in the backend too. I have also a place for blockchain interest.

EDUCATION

EDUCATION

ENGLISH B2/C1

• 2014-2017

ISTEA - TERCIARY DEGREE
Superior Software Development Technician

EPIC REACT BY KENT D. DOODS - HTTPS://EPICREACT.DEV/

CSS IN JS BY JOSH W COMEAU - HTTPS://CSS-FOR-JS.DEV/

REACTJS DEVELOPMENT BY UTN - HTTPS://SCEU.FRBA.UTN.EDU.AR/E-LEARNING/DETALLE/CURSO/1335/DESARROLLO-EN-REACT-JS

COMPLETE FLEXBOX CSS GUIDE BY UDEMY - HTTPS://UDEMY-CERTIFICATE.S3.AMAZONAWS.COM/PDF/UC-V7FI5RG2.PDF

CAREER SUMMARY

2022-2023
STACKZONE - REMOTE
SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

- PUSHED GOOD PRACTICES VIA CODE REFACTORING AND MENTORING.
- SUCCESSFULLY IMPLEMENTED COST-MANAGEMENT AND OPERATIONS FRONTEND MODULES.
- PUSHED CODE TYPING USING TYPESCRIPT
- UPDATED CORE LIBRARIES TO THE LATEST

2020-2021

SANTANDER TECNOLOGIA - REMOTESR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- WORKING ON CHECKS TEAM AS FRONTEND REFERENT.
- I WAS IN CHARGE OF DEVELOPING NEW MICROSITES WITHIN THE NEW PLATFORM FOR ENTERPRISES, INVOLVED IN USER EXPERIENCE, DEVELOPMENT, AND TESTING.

2018-2019

VALTECH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- WORKED BOTH BACKEND AND FRONT-END.
- SUCCESSFULLY DEPLOYED BACKOFFICE APIS (JAVA 8 SPRING BOOT).
- SUCCESSFULLY DEPLOYED BACKOFFICE FRONTEND REACT APP. (REACT/CSS)

2021-2022

COMMIT STUDIO - REMOTELEAD DEVELOPER

- AS A LEAD DEVELOPER, MY ROLE IMPLIES BOTH BRINGING SUPPORT TO TEAMMATES AND DEVELOPING NEW PRODUCTS AND FEATURES.
- SUCCESSFULLY IMPLEMENTED CREDIT PARTNER PLATFORM FOR PEDIDOSYA

2019-2020

PARKASSIST

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- WORKING ON THE NEXT-GEN PARKING ADMINISTRATION PLATFORM. (REACT/AWS)
- I'VE DEVELOPED PERFORMANT FEATURES ON THE CLIENT SIDE AND I'VE BEEN IN CHARGE OF SETUP CONFIGURATIONS ON DIFFERENT AWS SERVICES (IAM, IOT, S3).

2011-2018

OTHER COMPANIES

BACKEND SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- WORKED WITH JAVA 6 7 AS A JAVA DEVELOPER
- WORKED WITH ORACLE DATABASES
- ORACLE DATABASE DEVELOPER
- SUPPORT ANALYST